Aaron Plunkett

Data Analyst/Software Developer

Contact Information:

201 Middleton St, Apt 403 Nashville, TN 37210 (601) 213-7774

Email: aaroncpjob@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/aaroncp

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/aaronplunkett/

PROFILE

A natural leader and passionate problem solver. An extroverted developer who enjoys the public speaking, presentations, and group work that many shy away from. Because I also enjoy exploring data and the creativity that data visualizations allow, I am working to grow professionally in both software development and data analytics.

RELATED SKILLS	Languages	Environments	Tools/Methods
Well Versed	Java, Oracle SQL, PostgreSQL	Eclipse, Spring Tool Suite, pgAdmin, Oracle SQL Manager, Windows	Spring Boot, Hibernate/JPA, Thymeleaf, Excel, Google Sheets, Agile, Subversion, YouTrack
Experienced	HTML, Python, Ruby on Rails, C++, Visual Basic	GitHub, Jupyter Notebooks, RubyMine, Visual Studio	Git, Jira
Exposure To	C, CSS, Javascript	Power BI, Tableau, Aptana, Netbeans	Lucidchart

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst Apprenticeship Nashville Software School, Nashville, TN

January 2021

NSS provides hands-on training in all stages of the analytics workflow via group projects using real data from local companies. By using Excel, Google Sheets, Python, PostgreSQL, Tableau, Power BI, and Git/GitHub, a real-world Agile team environment is cultivated.

https://github.com/aaroncp/metro-e911-project

- Worked with Nashville 911 to analyze storm data and potentially improve future response
 - Generated heat map of storm calls and dispatches in Python to show areas that needed more attention
 - Plotted the time of calls and dispatches on a map to show where to adjust response time
 - Compared Covid heat maps to those of the storms to show impacted areas that need extra caution when responding
 - Highlighted areas that were both low income and hit by the storms to be most considered for aid efforts

https://github.com/aaroncp/nashville-cemetery-burials

- Worked with Nashville City Cemetery data to help create advertising
 - Found noteworthy graves and their location to be marked on a map
 - Showed areas of the cemetery that had a high concentration of Civil War or slave burials to increase traffic from Civil War enthusiasts
 - Analyzed causes of death to provide interesting historical medical information to tourists
 - Used a variety of methods to clean up a very messy data set for better and easier analysis

Associate Software Developer

Cybera Inc., Franklin, TN

June 2013 – April 2020

- Worked in Java with Spring Boot and Thymeleaf on web-based tools to allow customers to monitor the status of their sites and devices
 - Actively worked with front end developer to create any necessary CRUD methods
 - Helped plan the PostgreSQL database schema via Lucidchart to keep data access efficient and intuitive
 - Wrote most model and JPA repository files
 - Added voice, SMS, email, and QR Code 2FA methods
 - Implemented auditing throughout
- Created and improved features for internal customer tracking software using Java
- Implemented a new issue/tickets interface that both streamlined the assignment of, and reduced the time to resolve tickets
- Worked in a small team using the Agile methodology and Jira/YouTrack to improve productivity
- Assisted in the development of a tool in Ruby on Rails that automates bulk updates to customer information via Oracle SQL

Cooperative Education Program

Triton Systems of Delaware, LLC., Long Beach, MS

January 2010 - April 2010; August 2010 - December 2010; May 2011 - June 2011

- Debugged internal testing programs in Visual Basic
- Solved hardware problems with ATMs causing errors in the field to maintain customer satisfaction
- Discussed new design issues with engineering department to continue product innovation
- Interfaced with other departments and shouldered any excess work to get familiar with the whole business
- Collaborated with outside vendors to help evaluate possible future product use to drive down price and/or improve processing speed

EDUCATION

Data Analytics Bootcamp

Nashville Software School, Nashville, TN.

Graduating in January 2021

B.S. Double Major: Computer & Electrical Engineering

Double Minor: Mathematics & Japanese Mississippi State University, Starkville, MS.

August 2006 – December 2012

Japanese Language Study Abroad

Yamasa Institute, Okazaki City, Aichi Prefecture, Japan.

July – December 2011

- Completed course work in the Japanese language in a full-immersion classroom setting
- Learned to effectively convey ideas and make connections in an unfamiliar environment and culture
- Studied with a group of multinational students from diverse countries